艾玛·里格斯  纽约警察  开门
Emma Riggs, N.Y.P.D. Open the door!
我们能听见你在里面的动静  快开门
We hear you moving around in there! Open up!
33D报告总部  请求立即增援
33 David to central requesting immediate backup.
遭遇疑似谋杀嫌疑犯
Possible homicide suspect.
白人女性  棕色头发
White female, brown hair,
从西南逃生梯逃跑
fleeing down southwest fire escape.
拦住她
Stop her!
-对不起  你在干什么  -大家都不许动
- Excuse me? What are you doing? - Nobody move!
天啊
Oh, god!
卡塞尔
Castle...
-你睡着了吗  -是的
- Are you asleep? - Yes.
那你为什么回答我
Then why'd you answer me?
我在说梦话
I'm sleep-talking.
又叫梦呓
Also known as somniloquy.
别管我
Just ignore me.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
我有个主意
I have some ideas.
不  卡塞尔  我是说我的生活
No, Castle. I'm talking about my life.
我不知道该怎么继续生活
I don't know what to do about my life.
我15岁开始就一直在工作
I haven't been out of work since I was 15.
我无法相信联调局炒了我
I cannot believe that the F.B.I. fired me,
我也没办法回到纽约警局
and I can't get my job back at the N.Y.P.D.
因为警督那愚蠢的聘任冻结
Because of the commissioner's stupid hiring freeze.
我干脆申请当超市保安算了
I might as well just apply to become a mall cop.
你在电动代步车上一定很拉风
You would look great on a Segway.
但是  贝克特
But, you know, Beckett,
你没必要立马决定
you don't have to decide right away.
拜托  卡塞尔  你在说什么呢
Come on, Castle. What are you saying?
不决定我干什么  每天早上都睡懒觉
What am I gonna do, just sleep in every morning
混日子  直到电话响起吗
and screw around till the phone rings?
-那是什么样的生活啊  -我的
- What kind of life is that? - Mine.
对不起
Sorry.
我只是说你现在和我在一起
I just mean that you're with me now.
没必要工作
You don't have to work.
我没必要工作
I don't need to work?
那是说你是我的甜心干爹吗
Does that mean you're my sugar daddy?
等等  那听起来不...
Hold on. That didn't... come out--
其实我还在说梦话
Actually, I'm still sleep-talking.
不管我说了什么都不算数
I can't really be held responsible for whatever I say.
就算你们在吵架
Even when you're fighting,
-也超有爱  -派
- you two are super cute. - Pi.
早上好  C先生  未来的C太太
Morning, Mr. C., Mrs. C.-to-be.
介意我借用剃须刀吗
Hey, uh, do you mind if I borrow a razor?
当我用阿丽克西斯
Alexis gets all fired up
刮腿毛的剃刀时  她大发雷霆
when I shave with the one she uses for her legs.
-在洗脸池下面  -在洗脸池下面  好
- Under the sink. - Under the sink. Yep. Cool.
-他怎么还睡在你家沙发上  -我不知道
- Why is he still sleeping on your couch? - I don't know.
早上好  亲爱的
Good morning, darlings.
-怎么都不敲门  -门是开的
- Doesn't anyone knock? - Door was open.
别大惊小怪  这里发生的一切
Don't be an old maid. Nothing going on here
我都见过  以前也做过
that I haven't seen and done before.
有什么能帮你的  妈妈
So how can I help you, mother?
你知道的  我的工作室在刷漆
As you know, my studio is being painted,
所以我要在客厅里
so I am having my stage combat class
上表演课  就在15分钟后
in the living room in-- whoo-hoo--15 minutes,
想来的话欢迎啊
So, please, feel free to join.
三重刀片的剃须刀  不错啊  C先生
Triple blade razors! Nice, Mr. C.!
我打算今晚还是回家去睡
You know what? I think I'm gonna sleep at my old place tonight.
-我和你一起去  -怎么  在开家庭聚会吗
- I think I might join you. - What is this, a house meeting?
-不是  -不是
- No. - No.
盖茨警监打来了电话
Captain Gates is on the phone.
她找你  老爸
She's asking for you, dad.
喂
Hello?
谢谢你过来  卡塞尔先生
Thanks for coming, Mr. Castle.
还有你  贝克特
You, too, Beckett.
再次致歉  你没能恢复原职
Again, I'm sorry your reinstatement didn't work out.
谢谢  这里什么情况
Yeah. Thanks. So what do we got?
安其罗·瓦奎斯在他女友的公寓里被捅死
Angelo Vazquez, stabbed to death in his girlfriend's apartment,
这是瓦奎斯先生
and this is Mr. Vazquez.
你是想让我利用我的专业知识
And you are calling on my expertise
查出凶手
to unmask the killer.
不  其实我们已经确认了嫌犯的身份
No. Actually, We've already I.D.'d the suspect.
她是死者的女友  艾玛·里格斯
She's the victim's girlfriend-- Emma Riggs.
-你怎么知道是她  -因为她逃离了现场
- How do you know it's her? - Because she fled from the scene
还在这条街的一家牙科诊所挟持了人质
and took hostages in a dental office up the street.
好吧  这事和我有什么关系
Oh, okay. So this involves me how?
人质谈判专家试图和艾玛交谈
Hostage negotiators have been trying to talk to Emma,
但她要求只和你说话  卡塞尔先生
but she's demanding to speak to only you, Mr. Castle.
-我  为什么是我  -我们还希望你能告诉我们呢
- Me? Why me? - We were hoping you could tell us.
她看起来眼熟吗
Is she familiar to you?
我以前从没见过她
Uh... I've never seen her before.
-我们对她了解多少  -目前为止不多
- What do we know about her? - Not much so far.
艾玛·里格斯  31岁  服务员  无案底
Emma Riggs, 31, waitress, no record--
至少目前为止
At least until now.
队长
Sergeant?
这是人质谈判小队的罗曼队长
This is Sergeant Roman from the hostage negotiating team.
这是理查德·卡塞尔和凯特·贝克特
Richard Castle and Kate Beckett.
是副局长
Uh... ooh. Deputy chief.
先失陪了
Excuse me.
卡塞尔先生  你愿意通过电话
Mr. Castle, are you open to talking to Emma
-和艾玛交谈吗  -当然  能帮上忙就好
- over the phone? - Yeah, of course. Anything I can do to help.
里面什么情况
So what's the situation inside?
对我们的营救而言不大理想
It's not ideal for our purposes.
诊所的窗户被盖住了
The windows in the office are covered,
只有一扇门出入
and there's only one door leading in or out.
不能钻入光纤吗
Can't you just drill in fiber optics?
水泥太厚了  但我们已经确定
Cement's too thick. But we have ascertained
她挟持了五名人质
that she's taken five hostages--
牙医阿布·科根
The dentist-- Dr. Abe Kogan,
他的接待员苏·威廉姆斯  病人米奇·热拉尔
his receptionist-- Sue Williams, patient Mickey Gerhardt.
还有九岁的苏琪·钟
And Suki Chung, who's 9 years old,
以及她妈妈丽莎
and Suki's mother Lisa.
里面有个九岁的小孩吗
There's a 9-year-old in there?
但是如果我说错了话呢
But what if I say the wrong thing?
我会一直陪着你
I'll be with you the whole time.
我们会打通电话  看看大家怎么样
We'll make contact, see how everyone's doing,
试探一下她  弄清楚她想要什么
take Emma's temperature, find out what she wants.
然后我们一起想计划
And then we'll put a plan together.
你只用说话
All you have to do is talk.
如果说你有一件擅长的事  卡塞尔
Well, if there's one thing you excel at, Castle,
那就是说话
it's talking.
准备好了吗
You ready?
没有  但开始吧
No, but let's do this anyway.
-喂  -喂  艾玛  我是理查德·卡塞尔
- Hello. - Hello, Emma. This is Richard Castle.
听说你想和我谈谈
I heard you wanted to speak with me.
我怎么知道真的是你
How do I know it's really you?
如果你愿意走出门来
Uh, well, if you care to step outside,
我很乐意给你看我的驾照
I'd be happy to show you my driver's license.
那不可能
That's not gonna happen.
你说你是理查德·卡塞尔
Okay, you say you're Richard Castle?
那你就要证明
You're gonna have to prove it, all right?
在《妮基·希特》系列中
In the "Nikki Heat" series,
-鲁克和妮基喝什么酒  -桑塞尔干白
- what's Rook and Nikki's wine of choice? - Sancerre.
《致命热浪》中道格拉斯·桑德曼的外号是什么
In "Deadly Heat," What's Douglas Sandmann's nickname?
"臭虫"道格
Bedbug Doug.
《斯道姆崛起》中
In "Storm Rising,"
皮埃尔·杜布瓦的遗言是什么
What's Pierre Dubois' last words?
陷阱问题
Ah! Trick question.
皮埃尔是个特拉普会的修道士
Pierre was a Trappist monk.
他许过沉默誓言  他从不说话
He took a vow of silence. He never spoke.
现在相信是我了吧  艾玛
Boom! Believe it's me now, Emma?
我可以跟你玩一整天理查德·卡塞尔周边冷知识
Because I could play Richard Castle trivia with you
竞猜游戏  你输定了
all day. I will crush you.
好吧  是你
Okay. It's you.
-让我问你几个问题  -不不不
- So let me ask you a few questions. - No, no, no, no, no, no.
不能在电话里说  警察们听着呢
Not on the phone. The cops are listening.
-那又怎样  -我不相信他们  好吗
- So? - So I don't trust them, okay?
到牙医办公室来跟我谈
Just come inside the dental office and we can talk here.
-你在开玩笑吧  -闭嘴
- You've got to be kidding. - Hey! Shut up!
-听着  艾玛  -我们得面谈  听见了吗
- Uh, look, Emma... - We need to speak face-to-face. Do you hear me?
这是唯一的办法
It is the only way.
好  但你得把苏琪和她妈妈送出来  成吗
Okay, but only if you send out Suki and her mother. Deal?
成  五分钟之后到门口
Deal. Be outside in five minutes.
天啊  卡塞尔  你到底在想什么
God, Castle, what the hell were you thinking?
我不知道
I have no idea.
说实话  我没想到她会答应我的条件
Honestly, I didn't think she would take the deal,
但她是我的书迷
But, look, she's a fan.
我了解我的书迷  她不会伤害我
Okay? I know my fans. She won't hurt me.
你怎么知道
You don't know that.
我不是不知道风险
I'm not blind to the risks,
但我已经让她交出了小女孩和她妈妈
but I already got her to give up a little girl and her mother.
我可以劝动她
I can reach her.
也许可以让她投降
Right? Maybe even get her to surrender?
所以让我进去吧
So let me go in.
目标是进去再出来  明白吗
The goal is to get in and get out, you understand?
了解她的要求  查看人质的状况
Get her demands, check the status of the hostages,
然后记住所有人的位置
and make mental notes of where everyone is.
如果我们要冲进去的话会有帮助
That'll help us if we have to breach.
-你听见了吗  -要求  状况和位置  懂了
- You with me so far? - Demands, status, mental notes--got it.
如果有情况  我的意思是
And if anything-- and I mean anything--
任何情况   告诉艾玛你要给我们打电话
seems off, tell Emma you have to call us.
告诉她你是为了确保我们
Tell her it's to make sure that we're not gonna
-不做蠢事  好吗  -好的
- do anything stupid, okay? - Okay.
所以我们需要一个暗号
So we're gonna need a code word
以便你通知我们你需要帮助
that tells us that you need help.
你最喜欢的食物是什么
What, uh, what's your favorite food?
我们是在说日常食物还是精致的美食
Oh. Um... are we talking everyday food, or fine dining?
-如果包括甜点的话  -芝士汉堡
- If desserts are included... - Cheeseburgers.
-他爱吃芝士汉堡  -我确实爱吃芝士汉堡
- He loves cheeseburgers. - I do enjoy a good cheeseburger.
好吧  如果有情况
Okay. Anything goes wrong,
打电话  提到芝士汉堡  我们就进去
call, mention cheeseburgers, and we'll come running.
祝你好运
Good luck in there.
谢谢
Thank you.
芝士汉堡
Cheeseburgers.
听着
Listen...
我还期待着跟你一起
I'm kinda looking forward to spending
共度余生呢  所以
the rest of my life with you, so...
在里面别做傻事  好吗
Don't do anything stupid in there, okay?
别担心
Hey, don't worry.
我觉得我今天已经达到"犯傻"上限了
I think I already hit my "stupid" quota for the day.
天呐  真的是你
My god. It really is you.
那么可以放人了吗
So we have a deal?
快点  快点
Come on. Come on!
走吧  进来
Let's go, come in!
-你们怎么样  -你觉得我们怎么样
- How you guys doing? - How the hell you think we're doing?
-我说了让你闭嘴  -艾玛  冷静
- Hey! I told you to shut up! - Okay--Emma--Emma, easy!
我现在来了  对吧  我们谈谈吧
I'm here now, all right? So let's talk.
你想告诉我你的要求吗
You want to tell me your demands?
你是什么意思  要求
What do you mean, demands?
钱  离开这里的交通方式
Uh, money, transportation outta here?
不  我不要  我不要那些
No, no, I-I don't-- I don't want any of that.
好吧  那你要什么
Okay, then what do you want?
你  我只想  我只想要你
You. I just-- I just want you.
你要我
You want me?
我男朋友死了
My boyfriend is dead.
我知道局面对我不利
And I know what it looks like.
我知道  看起来像是我杀了他
I do. I know it. It looks like I killed him.
但我没杀他  我没有
But I didn't kill him. I didn't.
-闭嘴  -艾玛  拜托
- Shut up! - Emma, please.
保持冷静
Stay calm.
我知道你的能力
I know what you're capable of,
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle,
你能解决谋杀案
how you solve murders.
你想知道要求  好吧
You want demands? Okay.
我要让你证明我的清白
I want you to prove my innocence.
-她想让你证明她的清白  -对
- So she wants you to prove her innocence? - Right.
虽然我不想这么说
So I hate to break it to you,
但我觉得这不是一次
but I don't think this is going to be
传统的人质谈判
a traditional hostage negotiation.
为什么是你
Why you?
她看过我所有的书  所有关于
She's read all my books, all those articles
我和你一起破谋杀案的文章
about you and I working homicides together.
也就是说她是你的头号粉丝
So she's your number-one fan
而这一切是她对你示好的手段
and this is some sort of hail mary?
差不多吧  我觉得我们应该
Pretty much. So look, I think we should...
别跟他们说别的了
Don't tell them anything else.
为什么
Why?
因为  他们是警察
Because... they're cops.
你在里面还好吗  卡塞尔先生
Are you okay in there, Mr. Castle?
我还好  我会跟她谈谈
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm just-- I'm just gonna talk to her,
-然后给你们打回去  -你确定吗
- and then I'll call you back. - Are you sure?
对  不要芝士汉堡
Yes. No cheeseburgers.
再说一遍  不要芝士汉堡
I repeat-- no cheeseburgers.
正在减少红肉的摄入
Cutting down on red meat.
-我们现在该怎么办  -等
- So what do we do now? - We wait.
-但是我  -但是什么
- But I... - But what?
-长官  -抱歉
- Sir? - Excuse me.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
-长官  你确定那女人没案底吗  -怎么了
- Sir, are you sure that this woman doesn't have a record? - Why?
因为她看起来非常不信任警察
Because she seems to have a deep mistrust of the police.
显然  还有些东西
Well, obviously, there's more to it
不在系统资料里
than what's in the system.
我知道我已经不在这工作了  但
Look, I know I'm not on the job anymore, but...
你想去检查犯罪现场
You want to work the crime scene.
多一双眼睛也没什么坏处
It can't hurt to have an extra pair of eyes.
而且我们对艾玛了解得更多
And the more we find out about Emma,
我们救出卡塞尔和人质们的可能性
the better chance we'll have of getting castle
-就越大  -去吧
- and the hostages... - Go.
好吧  艾玛
All right, Emma.
你没杀你的男友
So... you didn't kill your boyfriend.
我们来想想是谁杀的
Let's figure out who did.
我的所有故事的开头都是
As you know, all my stories start in the same place
一样的  告诉我发生了什么
in the beginning. So tell me what happened.
-我昨晚回家晚了  -你为什么回家晚了
- I got home late last night. - Why did you get home late?
下班之后  我  我买了条裙子
Well, after work, I-I-- I, um, I bought a dress.
因为今天是我的生日
Because today's my birthday. Um...
安其罗本来今晚会带我出去吃饭
Angelo was, uh, was gonna take me out to dinner tonight.
他有惊喜给我
He worked out some sort of surprise.
说这会是我一辈子都忘不掉的生日
Said it'd be a birthday I'd never forget, so...
知道是什么样的惊喜吗
Any idea what the surprise was?
求婚吧
A marriage proposal.
至少我  我是这么希望的
At least I was-- that's what I was hoping.
所以我才买了那条裙子
That's why I bought the dress,
虽然我买不起  很傻  对吧
even though I couldn't afford it. Just stupid, huh?
不  一点都不傻
No. Not at all.
你买了裙子  然后呢
So you have your dress, and...
我回到家
When I got home, I, um,
给自己倒了两指高的威士忌
I poured my nightly two fingers of Scotch.
威士忌女孩  我也是
Scotch girl? Me, too.
男孩
Boy.
然后呢
And then what happened?
早上起来的时候
When I woke up in the morning, I...
发现安其罗在地上
I found Angelo on the floor,
死了
dead.
好多好多血
There was so much blood. It was...
我不知道发生了什么
but I don't--I don't-- I don't know what happened.
我甚至连
I, um... I don't even know
安其罗为什么会在我家都不知道
why Angelo was at my apartment in the first place.
-然后你做了什么  -我吓坏了
- Well, what did you do? - I-I panicked.
想出去  结果
Tried to get out of there, and the--
警察来了
the cops came, and...
我就逃到这来了
Here I am.
是啊  用枪挟持我们  真是个疯子女友
Yeah, holding us at gunpoint. Talk about a psycho girlfriend.
-你说什么  -你想害死我们吗
- What did you say?! - Are you trying to get us killed?
艾玛  放松
Okay, okay. Emma, relax.
别理他  把注意力放在我身上
Ignore him. Just focus on me, all right?
-安其罗有你家的钥匙吗  -有
- Did Angelo have a key to your place? - Yes.
但昨晚你没让他过来
But you didn't make any plans for him to come over last night?
对
No.
你们的恋情如何
How were things going in the relationship?
-没问题吧  -没有
- No problems? - Mnh-mnh. None.
你喝了多少酒
How much Scotch did you have?
一杯  两指高
One glass. The--the two fingers.
我需要你再给我捋一遍
I'm gonna need you to walk me through this again.
姑娘  你怎么来了
Girl, what are you doing here?
盖茨警监说我可以来
Uh, Captain Gates said that I could come.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
你不是应该在看婚礼场地什么的吗
Shouldn't you be off looking at wedding venues or something?
没  我们连时间都没定
No, we haven't even set a date.
我们只想享受订婚的欢乐时光
We're just trying to enjoy our engagement.
为什么每个人都在催我们
Why is everyone trying to rush us?
你以为这就算催了吗
Think you're being rushed now,
等婚礼之后吧
wait until after the wedding.
刚下圣坛不到十分钟  所有人都会问
Not ten minutes from the altar, they'll all be like,
"你们什么时候生小宝宝啊"
"When are you two having a baby?"
兄弟  你老婆情绪不稳定是因为怀孕了
Bro, your wife's hormonal because she's pregnant.
你又是为什么呢
What's your excuse?
我猜这是艾玛的男友
So I take it this is Emma's boyfriend?
曾经是  直到她拿了厨房的刀子
He was, until she stabbed him three times with a knife...
刺了他三刀
from the kitchen butcher block.
艾玛声称自己是无辜的
Emma's claiming that she's innocent.
有没有可能是别人做的
Is there any chance that someone else did this?
没有其他纤维和指纹
No foreign fibers or prints.
所有的证据都指向艾玛
All evidence is pointing towards Emma.
-有动机了吗  -有
- Any ideas on motive? - Oh, yeah.
这是安其罗的手机
This is Angelo's cell phone.
看他和艾玛发的短信
Check out the text history between him and Emma.
她指责他与斯卡斯代尔的
She was accusing him of having an affair
某个小妞有染
with some chick up in Scarsdale.
我们在安其罗的口袋里发现了这个
And we found this in Angelo's pocket.
锯木厂河公路  SH
"S.H. off Saw Mill River Parkway."
锯木厂河公路是从纽约
Saw Mill River Parkway is the way to Scarsdale
去斯卡斯代尔的路
from the city.
SH可能是和他约会的女孩名字首字母
"S.H." could be the initials of the lady he was seeing on the side.
听听这个
A-and listen to this--
昨晚9:47艾玛给安其罗发短信
Emma texts Angelo last night at 9:47
说她喝多了  很寂寞  想要见他
saying she's drunk, lonely, and wants to see him.
一个空的威士忌酒瓶
And here is an empty bottle of Scotch.
女士们先生们  这是深夜打炮进展不顺的结果
Ladies and gentlemen, this is a booty call gone wrong.
这些都讲不通啊
None of this makes any sense.
如果真是她杀了他
I mean, if she actually killed him,
为什么不要求去国外的机票
then why isn't she asking for a flight out of the country?
而是坚持让我们证明她的清白
why is she insisting that she's innocent?
也许她不正常
Uh, maybe because she's crazy.
我找到了她的处方药
I found Emma's prescriptions--
氯硝西泮和阿立哌唑
Clonazepam and aripiprazole.
蕾妮  这些都是治疗精神病的吧
Lanie, aren't those antipsychotics?
有一个是  另一个是治疗情绪紊乱的
One is, the other one's for mood disorders.
如果艾玛停药的话
Hey, you know, if Emma stopped taking her meds,
她可能会精神崩溃
she could have had a psychotic break.
也就是说她可能忘记自己做了什么
Which means she wouldn't remember what she did.
-我得提醒卡塞尔  -贝克特  淡定
- We have to warn Castle. - Beckett, relax.
他只是和那个女打电话而已
He's just on the phone with the woman.
不  他进去了
No. He went in.
好吧  等会打给你
Okay. Let me call you back.
贝克特探长有发现了吗
Did Detective Beckett find anything?
艾玛  如果你不和我说实话  我没办法帮你
Emma, I can't help you if you're not honest with me.
我说的都是实话
But I have been honest.
你说你和安其罗之间没有问题
You said everything between you and Angelo was all right.
对啊
Yeah, it was.
那你没怀疑过他出轨咯
So you didn't suspect him of cheating?
没有  只是他一直去斯卡斯代尔
No, it--it's just that he kept going up to Scarsdale
却不说为什么
without saying why.
-我确定那不重要  -确定吗
- I-I'm sure it was nothing. - Are you?
有没有可能  你想和他当面对质
Or could it be that you wanted to confront him?
所以你才在昨晚发短信给他
And maybe that's why you texted Angelo last night
让他去你家
and invited him over.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
看你的手机  艾玛
Look at your phone, Emma.
等一下  我没...
Wait, I don't...
我不记得我发过这些短信
No, I don't remember writing these texts.
你不记得不代表你没做过
Just because you don't remember doesn't mean you didn't.
就好像你只记得你喝了一杯威士忌
Just like you only remember having one glass of scotch.
但如果你喝了不止一杯呢
But what if you had more?
她们发现了你的酒瓶  艾玛  是空的
They found your Scotch bottle, Emma. It was empty.
我没有喝完一整瓶
I-I didn't finish the bottle.
也许你喝了  只不过忘记了
Maybe you did, and you just can't remember.
胡扯
That is ridiculous!
事实上这不是瞎说
Uh, um, a-actually, it's not.
如果一个人喝了太多
If someone's had too much to drink,
可能会暂时丧失意识
they can suffer what's called an en bloc blackout.
让大脑没办法制造新记忆
It prevents the brain from creating new memories.
艾玛  你想让我
Emma, you wanted me...
揭露真相
to uncover the truth.
不
No.
你不能也这样
Not you.
求你  别告诉我你也不相信我
Please don't tell me that you don't believe me.
我没有杀安其罗
I didn't kill Angelo, okay?
我想嫁给他
I mean, I-I wanted to marry him.
我不会这么做的
I wouldn't do this!
天啊
Oh, god.
天啊  我...
God... did I? I--
万一真的是我
What if I did? I don't...
怎么了
What?
你怎么写"爱你"
How do you text "Love you"?
什么意思
What do you mean?
当你写"爱你"的时候  你怎么拼的
When you write "Love you," how do you spell it?
打一个横躺的心再加字母"U"
Do a sideways heart and the letter "U."
没错  除了昨晚
Right, except for last night,
你把它完整拼了出来  "爱你"
when you just spelled it out-- "Love you."
不可能  我从不把它拼完整
No. I never spell it out.
而且昨晚短信的语气
And the voice in those texts from last night--
也和往常的不一样
it's--it's different from the others.
就像是别人写的吗
As if somebody else wrote them?
可能  我不确定
Maybe. I don't know.
如果这短信不是我写的
Well, if I didn't write these, that means
那就是另有其人  对吗
that somebody else did, right?
也就是说  凶手用了我的手机
Which means the killer used my phone!
你得把手机拿去验指纹
You have to dust this for prints.
快点  快  你得把凶手找出来
Come on. Come on. You have to find the killer.
-等等  什么  -你不会丢下我们不管吧
- Wait, what? - You're not leaving us, are you?
不  我会救你们出去
No. I-I'm gonna get you outta here.
说得跟真的似的
Like hell you are.
等着瞧吧  你和警察肯定不会有所行动
Look, if you or the cops aren't gonna do anything,
-我敢肯定  -闭嘴
- I sure as hell am. - Shut up!
你还在等什么  快  快走  行吗
What are you waiting for? Come on! Just go, okay?
米奇  别做傻事  拜托
Mickey, don't do anything. Please.
卡塞尔
Castle!
卡塞尔先生  怎么回事  里面什么情况
Mr. Castle, what happened? What is going on in there?
我们有麻烦了
We got problems.
退一步说  艾玛不太稳定
Emma is unstable, to say the least.
但这还不是最糟的  里面有个人质
But that's not the worst of it. There's a hostage in there--
看多了《虎胆龙威》
He's seen "Die Hard" too many times.
他总想在那儿充英雄
He's gonna try and be a hero.
还有件事我觉得你应该知道
And there's something else I think you need to know.
什么
What's that?
艾玛说的可能是实话
Emma might actually be telling the truth.
什么实话
The truth about what?
贝克特  我想她可能是被人栽赃的
Beckett, I think she's being framed for murder.
但万一艾玛是对的呢
But what if Emma is right?
如果真有人编辑了这些短信
What if someone else wrote those texts
这只是一个完美的栽赃证据
and this is all just an elaborate frame-up,
而艾玛是无辜的呢
and Emma's just a patsy?
句法  大哥  你居然只因艾玛写短信的方式
Syntax, bro? You're gonna base Emma's innocence
就想说明她是无辜的
on how she writes her texts?
我是说有可能
I'm just saying, it's possible.
听着  如果我们能在罪案现场发现
Look, if we found D.N.A. or prints
DNA  指纹或纤维  这还有可能
or fibers at the crime scene, maybe.
苏利  我们能从艾玛的手机上提取到有效指纹吗
Sully, we get any usable prints off Emma's cell phone?
不  但就算提取到了
No, but even if we did,
怎么能说明是别人发的呢
how could someone else have pulled this off?
要在她不知情的情况下用她的手机
To use her phone without her knowing,
艾玛肯定得处于神志不清的状态
Emma would have had to have been unconscious,
有可能是别人打晕了她
so someone could have knocked her out.
她每晚都喝酒
She has a scotch every night.
也可能是在她的酒瓶里下药
Someone could have dosed her bottle.
或者她可能就是个疯狂的粉丝
Or maybe she's just some crazed fan,
就像凯茜·贝茨在《危情十日》中演的
like Kathy Bates in "Misery."
你得庆幸你没摔断腿  不是吗
You should be happy you didn't get hobbled. Right?
好了  这是你的案子
Okay. This is your investigation.
继续在艾玛身上挖线索
Keep running the case on Emma.
-可是  警监  我...  -让我说完
- But, captain, I'm-- - Let me finish.
听着  卡塞尔先生  多年来
Look, Mr. Castle, over the years,
不论你的理论有多离奇
I have learned not to discount your little theories,
我已经学会了不去低估它们
no matter how fanciful.
你和贝克特与苏利警探合作
So why don't you and Beckett work with Detective Sully,
看看能不能查到什么
and let's see if there's something to this?
-谢谢  长官  -谢谢
- Thank you, sir. - Thank you.
我们从哪里开始
So, where do we start?
从我们的被害人  安其罗·瓦奎斯开始
By looking into our victim-- Angelo Vazquez.
所有线索都证明一件事
Everything here tells the same story.
安其罗是个好人
Angelo was a decent guy.
十年前  在小偷小摸后
Ten years ago, after some petty B&Es,
他走上正道
he turned his life around.
他在高危少年所做志愿工作  很受爱戴
He volunteered with at-risk youth, he was well-liked.
他最近丢掉了修理工的工作
He had been recently laid off from his mechanic's job,
但他很积极
but he was still upbeat.
看不出谁杀了他  也看不出为什么
There's nothing that explains who killed him or why,
除了艾玛
Other than Emma.
卡塞尔  你忘了斯卡斯代尔
Castle, you're forgetting about Scarsdale.
你认为艾玛的怀疑是真的
You think Emma's suspicious are true,
他有外遇
That he was having an affair?
斯卡斯代尔的女人杀了他
That some woman in Scarsdale killed him?
斯卡斯代尔有线索  你看
Well, something was going on in Scarsdale. Look at this.
三晚之前
Three nights ago,
-斯卡斯代尔住户投诉了安其罗的车  -为什么
- A resident complained about Angelo's car. - Why?
苏利怎么在他桌子上找东西的
How does Sully find anything on this desk?
不知道  他有自己的系统吧
I don't know. He must have a system.
-我认为那原来是个百吉饼  -你知道吗
- I think that was once a bagel. - Okay, you know what?
查一查
Here we go.
斯卡斯代尔眺望路的住户
A Scarsdale resident on overlook road
将安其罗的车牌报给警方
reported Angelo's license plate to the police.
他说司机整整两个小时  自己待在车里
He said the driver spent two hours drinking coffee
喝咖啡
alone in his car.
在车里喝两个小时咖啡
Two hours drinking coffee alone
不像是有外遇
doesn't sound like much of an affair.
是啊  但他想干什么呢
Yeah, but what was Angelo up to?
是苏利
Hey, it's Sully.
安其罗的公寓没有什么有趣的发现
There was nothing of interest at Angelo's apartment,
但他的车就是另一回事了
But his car is a whole other matter.
安其罗有个行李袋
Get this. Angelo had a duffel bag
装满了行窃用的工具
filled with tools of the burglar variety,
一栋房子的平面图
a floor plan to what looks like a house...
和一个兰柯-4700警报器的说明书
and a manual for a Ramco-4700 alarm system.
我认为他不是想安装报警系统
I don't think he was installing home security systems.
安其罗没了工作
Angelo was out of work.
你认为他又重操旧业了吗
Do you think he went back to committing B&E?
只有一个人知道这个答案
I only know one person with the answer to that question.
计划是这样的
Okay, here's the plan.
医生  你假装癫痫发作
Doc, act like you're having a seizure.
什么
Excuse me?
然后  苏  你挤出几滴眼泪
And then, Sue, you squirt out a few tears,
求艾玛帮他
Beg Emma to help him.
她一帮忙  我就制住她  一切就结束了
When she does, boom, I take her out, we end this,
然后咱在街角的酒吧碰面
then we meet at the bar around the corner,
第一轮酒我请
and the first round's on me.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
这是最烂的计划
That is the dumbest plan ever.
算了  我自己动手
Fine, I'll do it by myself.
是卡塞尔
It's Castle.
我带了甜甜圈
And I brought doughnuts.
无麸质的吗
Um... gluten-free?
老兄  这是甜甜圈  爱吃不吃
Dude, they're doughnuts. Either you're in or you're out.
有发现吗
You find out anything?
艾玛  关于安其罗总去斯卡斯代尔  你知道些什么
Emma, what do you know about Angelo's trips to Scarsdale?
不知道  他没跟我说过
Nothing. He wouldn't tell me.
他会不会是去踩点  准备入室盗窃
Is it possible he was there casing a house for a burglary?
什么...不  这太荒谬了
Wha--no. That's ridiculous.
大写字母S.H.  能让你想到什么吗
Do the initials "S.H." mean anything to you?
是不是安其罗又开始犯罪了
Could someone from Angelo's criminal past have come back?
那只是他年轻时犯的小错  仅此而已
Look, that was all petty stuff when he was a kid, that's all.
对  但他不再是个孩子了
Yes, but he wasn't a kid anymore.
风险更高了  他失业了
The stakes were higher. He was out of work.
想在你生日时给你个惊喜
He wanted to surprise you on your birthday,
说不定是求婚
Maybe propose.
如果他准备这些的时候惹上了麻烦呢
What if he got into trouble trying to make that happen?
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
卡塞尔人呢
Where's Castle?
他不在里面吧
He's not in there, is he?
-怎么了  -我们有发现
- Why? - We found something.
是关于艾玛的
Something about Emma.
艾玛
Emma.
放他们走吧
Let these people go.
已经可以了
It worked.
你把我引了过来  现在有希望了
You got my attention. There's hope now.
不
No.
证明我的清白之前  不行
Not until my name is cleared. No.
-贝克特的  -接吧
- It's Beckett. - Go.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett.
我告诉你件事儿不要有什么反应
Do not react to what I'm about to tell you.
好的
Okay.
艾玛从头到尾
Emma has been playing you
都在耍你
this whole time.
有意思  详细说一下吧
Interesting. Can you elaborate?
安其罗不是她手下第一个亡魂了  她以前也杀过人
Angelo is not her first victim. She's done this before.
她有一个封存的少年犯罪档案
She has a sealed juvie record
记录在原名之下  艾玛·琼斯
under her original name -- Emma Jones.
16岁时  她杀了寄养家的兄弟
When she was 16, she killed her foster brother--
比利·考斯
Billy Koss.
显然  她喝醉了
Apparently, she got drunk,
把他引到地下室
lured him into their basement,
然后用刀刺死了他
and then stabbed him with a knife.
那真是巧了
Well, that's a coincidence.
也表明了她的惯用手法  卡塞尔
Also known as an M.O. Castle,
她就是这么杀死安其罗的
It's exactly what she did to Angelo.
她情绪不稳定  你得赶快离开那里  马上
She's unstable. You need to get out of there--now.
什么都别说
Don't say another word.
挂掉
Hang up.
她把比利·考斯的事告诉你了  是不是
She told you about Billy Koss, didn't she?
-听着  艾玛  -退后
-Look, Emma... - Back up!
我不是杀人犯
I am not a murderer.
但你却拿枪指着我
Says the lady pointing a gun at me.
你们不该查比利·考斯的案子的
You weren't supposed to find out about Billy Koss.
如果警察想查就查
I mean, what is the point of a sealed record
那么封存档案有什么意义啊
when the cops can open it whenever they feel like it?!
他们肯定先拿到了传票
I'm sure they got a subpoena first.
肯定也会对那些描述我的形容词
And I'm sure they all had a laugh
拿来说笑  对吧
off all the adjectives describing me, right?
狂躁症  情感两极化  暴力  杀人犯
Manic. Bipolar. Violent. Murderer!
我不是要较真
Well, not to be a stickler,
但"杀人犯"不是形容词
but "murderer" isn't an adjective.
-我不是白痴  -抱歉
- I'm not an idiot. - Sorry.
我紧张的时候会挖苦别人
I just get sarcastic when I'm nervous.
我不是在说这个
That's not what I was talking about.
我知道你会怎么想
Look, I knew what you were going to think.
两起命案  同样的犯罪手法
Two deaths happening the exact same way?
所以我才没告诉你  但我是清白的
That's why I didn't tell you. But I am innocent!
我没杀安其罗  我没有
I didn't kill Angelo. I didn't!
如果这是真的  艾玛  你想让我帮你
If that's true, Emma, and you want me to help you,
就把一切都告诉我
you have to tell me everything.
我16岁的时候
When I was 16,
被送到这家寄养家庭
I was sent to this foster home.
有一对双胞胎孤儿住在那儿
Twin orphans lived there--
考斯兄弟
The Koss brothers.
沃伦和比利
Warren and Billy.
发生了什么
What happened?
他们两个欺负了我好几周
Those two bullied me for weeks.
寄养家父母要出去赚钱
Foster parents were in it for the money,
所以他们不关心
so they didn't care.
但后来有一天  双胞胎
But then one day, the twins
突然对我很好
were nice to me all of a sudden.
我就以为他们
And I thought they, um...
我以为他们终于接受我了
I thought they'd finally accepted me, you know?
于是我们
So we...
一起去了地下室
we went down to the basement.
我们喝了烈酒  然后...
We drank schnapps, and then...
比利拿刀刺向我
Billy pulled a knife on me.
我只是想阻止他
I was just trying to stop him.
不是故意要...
I didn't mean to...
后来警察来了
And then when the cops came...
沃伦撒了谎
Warren lied.
他说是我拿刀刺他们
He said I pulled the knife on them,
警察相信了他的话
And they just--they just took him at his word.
所以你讨厌警察
Which is why you hate cops.
但我没杀安其罗
But I didn't kill Angelo.
我没有  你必须相信我
I didn't. You have to believe me.
艾玛  我相信你
I do, Emma. I believe you.
但为什么安其罗和比利的死
But why were Angelo and Billy's deaths
布置得一模一样呢
staged exactly the same way?
我不知道  我不知道
I have no idea. I don't know.
一定是了解你过去的人做的
It has to be someone who knew something about your past.
-是啊  我猜也是  -那是谁呢
- Yeah. I mean, I guess so. - But who?
沃伦·考斯
Warren Koss.
有什么方法能比杀死你男友
What better way to get revenge for the death of his brother
然后嫁祸给你
than by killing your boyfriend
更能为兄报仇的呢
And pinning the murder on you?
不是沃伦
No, it's not Warren.
沃伦因为故意伤人
Warren's doing eight years
在新新监狱服刑8年
up in sing sing for assault.
-你一直关注着他  -当然
- You kept track of him? - Of course.
我是因为他才改名的
He's the reason why I changed my name.
我非常小心
I mean, I have been really careful
避开沃伦的生活范围
about staying off of Warren's radar
自从他在庭上指证我杀人之后
ever since he testified against me in court.
差点让我坐一辈子牢
He almost got me thrown in prison for life.
要不是那些
If it wasn't for the sisters
圣海伦娜儿童之家的修女们  我...
Of St. Helena's home for children, I--
慢着  再说一遍
Whoa, whoa. Go back.
-圣海伦娜儿童之家  在哪  -在扬克斯[纽约郊区]
- St. Helena's home for children--where is that? - In Yonkers.
我们在安其罗的外套里
The note we found in Angelo's jacket
发现写着"S.H.在锯木厂河路上"的便笺
said "S.H. off Saw Mill River parkway."
S.H.指的是圣海伦娜
"S.H." has to be St. Helena's.
扬克斯就在锯木厂河路上
Yonkers is off Saw Mill River parkway.
圣海伦娜跟这个联系到一块儿了
Somehow St. Helena's is connected to this.
但是怎么会  我好久没回那里了
But I--how? I mean, I haven't been back there in years.
我跟圣海伦娜的弗兰西斯修女联系过了
I spoke with sister Frances at St. Helena's.
她说三天前夜里曾有一次非法闯入
She said that there was a break-in three nights ago.
她们用的是兰柯-4700警报器
And they have a Ramco-4700 alarm.
兰柯-4700  安其罗车里有它的说明书
Ramco-4700. That's the manual Angelo had in his car.
他为什么要闯入我之前住的孤儿院
Why would he break into my old orphanage?
我们有个靠谱的想法
We have a pretty good idea.
弗兰西斯修女检查过了档案室
Sister Frances checked the records room.
艾玛密封的收养文件不见了
And Emma's sealed foster care file is missing.
看来是安其罗偷走的
Looks like Angelo stole it.
-他为什么这么做  -发现关于你的什么事
- Why would he do that? - To find out something about you?
不  我已经告诉他我的一切了
No, I already told him everything about me.
天啊
Oh, god.
回头打给你们  伙计们
Guys, let me call you back.
你知道原因了
You figured it out?
我一出生  就被送去领养了
I was given up for adoption when I was born.
安其罗知道我一直想弄清楚自己的身世
Angelo knew I always wanted to find out where I came from.
而那个文件有你的收养信息
And that file had your adoption papers
包括你亲生父母的名字
with your birth parents' names.
之前我试图拿到文件
I tried to get 'em in the past,
但是...  文件已经被封存
but... they were sealed.
这就是安其罗今晚想要给你的惊喜
That's the surprise Angelo was gonna give you tonight...
在你的生日晚餐上
At your birthday dinner.
礼物就是知道你的亲生父母是谁
The gift of knowing who your real parents are.
小心
Watch out.
住手  住手  不  听我说
Stop it! Stop it! No! Listen--
米奇
Mickey! Aah!
住手
Drop it!
所有单位  冲进去  快快
All units, full breach! Go, go, go!
天啊  我杀了理查德·卡塞尔
God! Oh, my god! I just killed Richard Castle!
纽约警察局  双手举起来
Oh! Oh! N.Y.P.D.! Let me see your hands!
是她干的  是她干的
It was her! It was her! It was her!
把他带出去
Get him up! Get him up!
-我们现在需要急救医生  快点  -卡塞尔
We're gonna need an E.M.T. Right away! Let's go! Castle!
卡塞尔
Castle!
芝士汉堡
Cheeseburgers!
Cheeseburgers.
真的有效
It worked.
她射在"I"上了
She dotted the "I"! Yeah!
我的胸  疼
Aah! Chest! Ooh!
-真疼  -抱歉  当然了
- That hurts. -Sorry. Yeah, well, getting hit by a projectile
被每秒一千尺速度运行的子弹射到不疼才怪
traveling at 1,000 feet per second's gonna sting a bit.
对  我想应该会留疤
Yeah, I think that's gonna leave a mark.
你没事就好了
All that matters is you're okay now.
我比没事更开心  贝克特
Oh, I'm better than okay, Beckett.
我知道凶手是谁了
I know who the killer is.
她往你胸部射了一枪
She shot you in the chest,
你还认为她是无辜的
and you still think she's innocent?
不  她射了我一枪
No, she shot me in the chest,
现在我知道她是无辜的了
and now I know she's innocent.
谢谢  你看不出来吗
Thank you. Don't you see?
就像避弹衣保护我一样
Just like that vest protected me,
艾玛的收养文件
Emma's adoption papers--
保护着凶手
they're protecting the killer.
那完全说不通
You know that made no sense, right?
我想卡塞尔是想说
I-I think what Castle is suggesting
艾玛的亲生父母
is that one of Emma's birth parents
也许就是幕后主使
may be behind all of this.
那也是安其罗拿走记录的原因
That's why Angelo took those records--
找到她的亲生父母  如果他找到了其中之一呢
to find her birth parents. What if he found one of them?
也许就住在斯卡斯戴尔眺望路上
Perhaps living on Overlook Road in Scarsdale.
如果她的亲生父母不想被找到呢
But what if that birth parent didn't want to be found?
如果艾玛知道真相对他们来说是个威胁呢
What if Emma learning the truth was a threat somehow?
卡塞尔  这只是猜测而已
Castle, that's just speculation.
如果你是对的  我们可能永远不会知道
And if you're right, we'll probably never know.
凶手现在很有可能已经毁掉了记录
The killer's most likely destroyed the records by now.
除非  安其罗藏了起来
Unless... Angelo hid them.
我是说  这本应是个惊喜
I mean, they were supposed to be a surprise.
再去安其罗的住所  我们要再搜查一遍
Head back to Angelo's place. We need to search it again.
你有意识到
You are aware that you don't actually
你已经不是警察了  对吧
work here anymore, right?
对不起  使唤习惯了
I'm sorry. Old habits.
好  我们会让苏利
Okay. Uh, we'll grab Sully...
再去搜查一遍  以防万一
go check again, just in case.
但不是因为你要求我这么做
But not because you asked me to.
是因为我正好要去...
Okay. 'cause I was actually on my way to...
好的  假设这是艾玛的生日礼物
Okay. So let's suppose it is one of Emma's birth parents.
如果安其罗被谋杀是为了诬陷
If Angelo's murder was a setup,
他们又怎么会知道如何布置呢
then how would they know how to stage it?
我是说  他们把她送去领养
I mean, they gave her up for adoption,
那他们怎么知道艾玛的暴力史
so how would they know about Emma's violent history?
-新闻报道  -不  我查过了
-Newspaper articles. - No. I checked.
因为她当时还是未成年人  名字没对外公布
Because she was a minor, her name was withheld.
那么凶手必须通过其他渠道拿到
So then our killer had to have had access
艾玛密封的青少年犯罪记录
to Emma's sealed juvie records.
这样的话  就需要传票
And for that, you need a subpoena.
看来有人直接跳过这一步了
Looks like someone skipped that step.
艾玛的密封档案三天前被打开过
Emma's sealed records were opened three days ago.
是谁打开的
By who?
是朱丽安·卡特吗
Julian Carter?
你好  我是莱恩警探  这位是凯特·贝克特
Hi. I'm Detective Ryan. This is Kate Beckett.
我们是十二分局的  能否耽误你些时间
We're from the 12th. Do you have a second
帮助我们件事
to help us out with something?
没问题  怎么了
Sure. What's up?
系统记录显示你打开了
The system tagged you for opening a file
艾玛·琼斯的文件
of an Emma Jones.
对  这就是我的工作
Yeah. That's my job.
打开文件  合上文件
I open files, I close files.
我正在归档文件
Right now I'm filing files.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
恐怕是的  那是青少年犯罪文件
I'm afraid so. You see, it was a juvie file,
而你没经法庭批准打开了
and you didn't have the court's permission to unseal it.
我有时候忘了注销我的电脑
Well, I... sometimes forget to log out of my computer,
-也许是有人  -别狡辩了
-so maybe somebody - just stop it.
你已经丢了饭碗  现在的问题是
You've already lost your job. Now the only question is
你是否也会失去自由
whether you're losing your freedom, too,
因为我们会以凶手从犯的罪名
because I'm about two seconds away from arresting you
-将你逮捕  -等等  等等
- for accessory to murder. - W-wait. Wait. Hold on.
在他掏出手铐之前你最好先交代清楚
You better start talking before he pulls out his cuffs.
好的好的  我说
Okay. Okay. Okay!
有时候  我会把信息透露给一个律师
From time to time, I slip information to a lawyer.
什么样的信息
What kind of information?
犯罪档案  证人证词之类的
Rap sheets, witness statements, things like that.
那艾玛的事呢
What about with Emma?
三天之前  那个律师打电话给我
Three days ago, the lawyer called,
说他的一个客户要所有
Said a client wanted all the information
关于艾玛·里格斯的警方信息
that the police had on Emma Riggs.
-有什么目的  -他没说
- What for? - He didn't say.
但当我告诉他艾玛有青少年犯罪文件
But when I told him that Emma had a juvie file
不过归在不同的姓氏之下
under a different last name,
他又额外付给我一千美元打开文件
He paid me an extra grand to unseal it.
那个律师叫什么名字
What's the name of this lawyer?
不  我和法官约好了吃午餐
No, I'm having breakfast with the judge--
你好  文斯先生  我是莱恩警探
Hi, Mr. Vance. I'm Detective Ryan.
他是一个朋友的朋友
Uh, he's a friend of a friend.
对  而且...
Yeah. And then--
他会给你回电话的
He's gonna need to call you back.
-你脑子有毛病吗  -事实上  文斯先生
- What is your problem? - Actually, Mr. Vance,
-有毛病的是你  -好吧  洗耳恭听
- You are. - Okay. I'm listening.
你受一名客户所托  通过贿赂  查阅了
On behalf of a client, you paid to have
艾玛·里格斯的少年犯罪记录
Emma Riggs' juvenile records unsealed.
购买封存警方文件是违法的
Buying secured police files is illegal...
而且会吊销律师资格证  我是绝不会做这种事的
and grounds for disbarment. I would never do that.
是吗  我可是有一位纽约警局文职人员
Really? Because I have an N.Y.P.D. civilian employee
他的说辞与你刚好相反  并且他愿意作证
who begs to differ. He's willing to testify to it.
警探  我不是惟利是图的小律师
Detective, I'm not some ambulance chaser.
我可是柯帕杨律师事务所受人尊敬的律师
I'm a respected attorney at Kirk Patrick & Young.
所以除非你能拿出什么实质证据
So unless you have any real proof of those claims,
不然你就别指望任何法庭
good luck getting any court to take the word
会听信一个渎职的文职人员的证词
of a disgraced civilian employee.
文斯先生  你的客户现在卷入了一起谋杀案
Mr. Vance, you have a client who's mixed up in a homicide.
你拒绝透露他的姓名  就是妨碍司法公正
By withholding their name, you're obstructing justice.
就算我想帮你  我也不能把客户的姓名透露给你
Even if I wanted to, I can't disclose my client's name.
你也清楚地知道  律师和客户之间是有保密协议的
As you're well aware, that falls under privileged information.
别跟我说律师那边碰壁了
Oh, don't tell me we struck out on the lawyer.
恐怕是的
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
那现在怎么办
So what do we do now?
拜托  如果我们不想点办法的话
Come on, you guys. If we don't figure this out,
艾玛就要在监狱里度过余生了
Emma is going away for life.
她的威士忌酒瓶子怎么样了  检验结果出来了吗
What about her scotch bottle? Did the lab report come back?
蕾妮刚刚发过信息来
Lanie just texted.
没有找到任何毒品或是镇定剂的残留
There's no evidence of any drugs or sedatives.
抱歉  不过看来我们走投无路了
I'm sorry. It looks like we're dead in the water.
不  此言差矣  猜猜我们在安其罗的公寓里找到了什么
No. Far from it. Guess what we found in Angelo's apartment.
安其罗为艾玛准备的生日礼物
Angelo's birthday present to Emma.
我之前没注意到是因为它包起来了
I missed it before because it was wrapped.
-我是想让他们猜的  -抱歉  我没
- I was...I was gonna have them guess. - Oh, I didn't...
据这些收养文件显示
According to these adoption papers,
艾玛的生母是一个名叫史黛西·摩尔的女人
Emma's birth mother was a woman named Stacy Moore.
她十年前过世了
She died ten years ago.
而她的生父是
And her birth father is...
埃斯波  这记录是真的吗
Espo, is this right?
是的  艾玛的父亲是亚伦·斯托克斯
It's right. Emma's dad is Aaron Stokes.
-那个著名的地产开发商吗  -没错
- The real estate developer? - Yeah.
他正在考虑竞选州长
He's considering taking a run at governor.
没错  我想知道州长府邸和他在斯卡斯代尔
Yeah, and I wonder how the governor's mansion
眺望路上的房子比起来哪个更大
compares to his big house on Overlook Road in Scarsdale.
让我猜猜  他是柯帕杨律师事物所的客户
And let me guess. He's a client of Kirkpatrick & Young.
没错
That's right.
看来斯托克斯先生
Looks like Mr. Stokes
要用他的大房子来换
is gonna be trading in his big house for the...
另一座"大房子"了
big...house.
你们传唤亚伦·斯托克斯来审问
You ordered Aaron Stokes in for questioning?
开什么玩笑
Are you serious?
你让我们彻查此案  而我们查到了斯托克斯先生
You told us to build our case, and Mr. Stokes is where it went.
这可是一个非常权高望重的人
This is a very powerful man
而他恰好又跟警督是高尔夫球友
who happens to be golfing buddies with the police commissioner!
就因为他跟你的上司是好基友
So because he has a standing tee time with your boss,
他就可以逃脱谋杀罪名吗
he gets away with murder?
我负责审问
I'm handling the interview.
什  什么  不  头儿
What -- what? No. Sir!
这是我们的案子
This is our case.
没错  一旦出了什么差错  丢工作的也是你们
Yes, And it'll be your jobs if there's any blowback.
我不会让你俩拿自己的职业生涯冒险
I am not gonna have you two risk your careers.
警监  我用不着担心我的职业生涯
Captain, I don't have a career to risk.
我跟你一同审问怎么样
How about I back you up in there?
好的
Okay.
警监  我也不担心
Captain, I, too, have no career to risk.
我何不  也许我应该
Why don't I -- maybe I should...
这样好了  我就老老实实待在这
You know what I'm gonna do, is I'm gonna stay here.
交给你俩了
I think you guys got this handled.
为什么叫我来
Why am I here?
你们知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
不知道就不会安排这间屋子了  斯托克斯先生
Why do you think you're in this room, Mr. Stokes?
这个房间没有录音或是录影设备
A room with no recording devices.
好吧
Okay.
那你们到底想问我什么
So what do you want from me?
我们知道当你跟你太太结婚的时候
We know that while you were married to your wife...
你还跟史黛西·摩尔有外遇
you were having an affair
并且你们生了个女孩
with Stacy Moore that produced a baby girl.
她叫艾玛·里格斯
Her name is Emma Riggs.
你有跟她联系过吗  斯托克斯先生
Have you been in touch with her, Mr. Stokes?
不  我之前从来没见过她
No, I've -- I've never seen her before.
那她的男朋友呢  安其罗·瓦奎斯
What about her Boyfriend? Angelo Vazquez.
你有跟他联系过吗
Have you been in touch with him?
没有  艾玛出什么事了吗
No. Is Emma in trouble?
可以这么说吧
Well, you could say that.
她由于谋杀安其罗而被捕了
She's under arrest for murdering Angelo.
但是别担心  我们知道她是被人陷害的
But don't worry. We know that she's being framed for that murder.
是谁陷害她
Who's framing her?
你知不知道安其罗窃取了她在圣海伦娜儿童之家的
Did you know that Angelo stole her adoption records
领养记录
from St. Helena's home for children?
圣海伦娜儿童之家
St. Helena's?
是我和史黛西去那里办的手续
Stacy and I went there to make the arrangements.
我还能怎样做  告诉我妻子
What was I supposed to do, tell my wife
我跟另外一个女人生了个孩子吗
I was having a baby with another woman?
31年了  我没有一天
31 years, and not a day has gone by
不对自己说"我应该试着去找她"
where I haven't said to myself, "I should try to find her."
也没有一天我不对自己说
And not a day has gone by where I haven't then said,
"不  不
"No, no...
还是等明天吧"
Maybe tomorrow."
今天是她生日
It's her birthday.
你还是没回答我的问题
You still haven't answered my question.
你知道安其罗盗取了那些领养文件吗
Did you know that Angelo stole those adoption records?
你们俩想说什么
What are you two getting at?
试着从我们的角度想想看  斯托克斯先生
Look at it from our perspective, Mr. Stokes.
你现在最不需要的
The last thing you need right now
就是突然冒出来一个私生女毁了你的婚姻
is for some love child to emerge and destroy your marriage
和你竞选公职的机会
and any chance of running for public office.
你是想说我和此事有关吗
Are you suggesting that I had something to do with this?
我们知道安其罗三天前曾去过你家
We know that Angelo showed up at your home three days ago.
你那时见过他吗
Did you meet him then?
三天前我在芝加哥
I was in Chicago three days ago.
如果你所言非虚  那你为什么
If that is true, then why did you pay
要花钱去解封艾玛的青少年犯罪记录呢
to unseal Emma's juvenile record?
你这是听谁说的
Where are you getting this?
你的律师  斯托克斯先生
From your lawyer, Mr. Stokes.
什么律师
What lawyer?
好吧  这简直就是警方骚扰
Okay, this is borderline police harassment.
如果你们继续这样违背我的意愿扣留我
If you continue to hold me here against my will,
-你们就得  -等一下
- you either need to -- - Just wait.
在你把律师那套搬出来之前
Before you get all lawyer-y,
我们已经把你的底细都查清楚了
we already know everything.
首先你是亚伦·斯托克斯的女婿
Starting with you being Aaron Stokes' son-in-law.
所以呢
So?
所以当你的岳父母出城的时候
So when your in-laws were out of town,
你就住在他们位于斯卡斯代尔的家中
you were staying in their Scarsdale house.
当安其罗去找斯托克斯先生时
So when Angelo went to go look for Mr. Stokes,
却遇到了你
He met you instead.
也就是在那时他跟你讲了
That's when he told you the story
斯托克斯先生失散多年的女儿艾玛的故事
about Mr. Stokes' long-lost daughter emma.
听着  是的
L-look. Yes,
我住在我岳父家
I stayed at my father-in-law's house,
但我这辈子从没见过这个人
but I've never seen this guy before in my life.
你确定  因为
Are you sure? Because...
这是安保录像
Well, this is security footage...
来自安其罗的公寓楼
from inside Angelo's apartment building
在他死于艾玛家一小时后拍下的
taken about an hour after his death down at Emma's place.
等等  这是谁啊
Now wait a minute. Who... who is that?
这是
That...
这是你
That's you.
在用安其罗的钥匙进屋
Using Angelo's keys to get in.
你怎么拿到的
How'd you get those?
我只能想到一个原因
Now I can only think of one reason
就是你闯入他的公寓
that you'd break into in his, uh, apartment,
想找到艾玛的收养记录
and that would be to find Emma's adoption records
来掩盖与你家有关的一切联系
to cover up any link back to your family.
通过录像所示
Now according to this video,
你进到了公寓里
you were inside that apartment
找了足足两个小时
searching for a good two hours.
糟透了
Damn...
你竟然没想到去看看
You didn't think to look...
包好送给艾玛的礼物
tt the wrapped gift for Emma,
没想到吧
Did you?
她的收养记录
Her adoption records.
直到那时  你的计划一切顺利
Up until then, your plan was going perfectly.
你给艾玛的威士忌里面注入了麻醉药
You spiked Emma's scotch bottle with knockout drops
然后换成了空瓶子
and you swapped it out for an empty one.
这招挺聪明
Th-that was pretty clever.
但没把有药的瓶子从家里扔掉就有点傻了
But not so clever to throw the dosed bottle away at your house.
对  我们从你的垃圾箱里找到了瓶子
Yeah. We found the bottle in your recycle bin.
检测出了水合氯醛
It tested positive for chloral hydrate.
糟透了  又一次
Oops again.
这都是间接证据
All of this is circumstantial.
我是说  我的动机是什么
I mean, what could possibly be my motive?
你岳父帮我想出来了
Oh, your father-in-law helped us out with that one.
你的律师事务所代理斯托克斯家族
Your law firm represents the Stokeses.
你知道他们要将
Now you knew that they were about to transfer
一大部分财产转到女儿的信托基金里
a majority of their wealth into a trust
也就是你的妻子
for their daughter-- your wife.
你不想要什么小孤儿安妮[音乐剧人物]
And you didn't want some little orphan Annie
忽然出现卷走一半
coming around, making a claim for half.
所以才会决定杀掉知道真相的人
That's when you decided to kill the one man who knew the truth
再嫁祸到这个不为人所知的继承人身上
and frame it on the unknowing heir.
只有一点我们不太确定
There's just one thing that we're not so sure about.
你打算协议认罪
Are you gonna make a deal and plea to murder?
还是冒险上庭
or you gonna take your chances in court?
律师有自己的律师吗
Do lawyers have lawyers?
艾玛
Emma?
他认罪了
He confessed.
结束了
It's over.
枪伤
Bullet.
对不起  对不起
Sorry. Sorry.
我希望你不要介意
Um, I hope you don't mind,
有人想见你
but someone wants to meet you.
我是亚伦
I'm Aaron.
艾玛
Emma.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
你回来真好
Nice having you back.
是啊  真好  虽然只是一天
Oh, it was nice to be back, even if it was just for one day.
斯托克斯先生  能为你做些什么
Mr. Stokes. What can we do for you?
早前  你们俩只是在做本职工作
Earlier, you two were only doing your jobs,
而我却误解了  我很抱歉
But I assumed the worst, and I'm... sorry.
-现在感觉怎么样  -不确定
- Well, how are you doing? - Not really sure.
但是我只知道
But I do know this.
这次我会陪着艾玛
I am going to be there for Emma this time.
无论她的案子会怎样
No matter what happens at her trial,
她都不会一个人孤军奋战
She's not going to be alone.
好了  我该让你们好好工作了
Well, I should leave the both of you to your work.
警监  谢谢你做的一切
Captain, thank you for everything.
你也是  探长
You, too, Detective.
事实上  我不是  但是
Uh, actually, I'm not a detective, but...
你不是吗
you are not
她应该是的
Oh, she should be
但和你一起打高尔夫的小伙伴
But your golfing buddy's budget cuts
因为财政削减阻碍了她回到岗位
have gotten in the way.
真的
Really?
遥想当初
And to think you boys mocked me
我弄这件防弹衣时你们还嘲笑过我
when I had this made four years ago.
我会把它裱起来了
I think I'll have it framed.
你的头号粉丝要杀你
Hey, what does it say about your writing
它又能说明你的作品怎么样呢
when your number-one fan tries to kill you?
这是个意外
That was an accident.
再高一点  就是悲剧了
Been one inch higher, it would have been a tragedy.
不过好的一面就是你们的签名版
But on the bright side, your autographed copies
《致命希特》就更值钱了
of "Deadly Heat" would be worth way more.
-一点都不好笑  卡塞尔  -有点好笑
- Not funny, Castle. - Little bit funny.
贝克特  除了你未婚夫差点死了
You know, Beckett, despite your fiance's near-death,
今天很有意思
today was fun.
真想念和你工作的日子
Yeah. We miss working with you.
很好
Good.
因为我回来了
'cause I'm back.
什么  发生什么
What? What hap--what--
那警督的聘任冻结呢
What about the commissioner's hiring freeze?
斯托克斯先生和警督谈过了
Mr. Stokes had a conversation with the commissioner,
很明显  他又找到钱了
and apparently he found some money.
所以你回来了
So you are back.
也意味着  我也回来了
Which means... I'm back.
我能回来吗
Am--am I back?
能  盖茨警监说你可以再当顾问
Yes. Captain Gates said that you can serve as a consultant again.
但是那个  我们的关系
But how does that-- because now we're in a--
我们要隐瞒我们的关系吗
So do we have to hide our relationship,
保密吗
to keep it a secret?
警督知道了
Uh, well, the commissioner is aware of it
说只要我们工作时表现专业一点
and said that it's okay as long as we behave professionally
就没问题  盖茨警监说
in the workplace, and Captain Gates said that
就当我们的订婚礼物了
that can be our engagement gift.
每个人  听好了
Hey, everybody, listen up.
贝克特回来了
Beckett is back!
Beckett's back!
今晚在"老地方"酒水免费
And tonight at the Old Haunt, drinks are on the house!
好了
All right!
-恭喜  -谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
哦  不行  我们不能  不能在这
Uh--whoa! Actually, no, we can't, not here.
不合适  这是工作场合
It's, uh, inappropriate. This is the workplace.
我们得专业
We gotta be professional.
你也知道  我明天才正式回来呢
Uh, well, you know, I'm not officially back until tomorrow.
懂了
I see.